<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Posts on FIGHT LIKE A CROW</title>
		<link>https://fightlikeacrow.com/posts/</link>
		<description>Recent content in Posts on FIGHT LIKE A CROW</description>
		<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 11:36:33 +0800</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://fightlikeacrow.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
		<item>
			<title>The Creative Writing Origin of QAnon</title>
			<link>https://fightlikeacrow.com/posts/the-creative-writing-origin-of-qanon/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 11:36:33 +0800</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://fightlikeacrow.com/posts/the-creative-writing-origin-of-qanon/</guid>
			<description>Media outlets have failed to report the likely creative writing origins of QAnon. This oversight is extremely important with respect to undermining the narrative of shameless QAnon aficionados who have turned a creative writing exercise into something between a doomsday cult and a pyramid scheme, with real life consequences.
In November 2017 a YouTube video creator working with two moderators of the 4chan website, began plugging specific anonymous posts (dated October 2017) pulled from amidst the many conspiracy theories posted on 4chan.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Media outlets have failed to report the likely creative writing origins of QAnon.  This oversight is extremely important with respect to undermining the narrative of shameless QAnon aficionados who have turned a creative writing exercise into something between a doomsday cult and a pyramid scheme, with real life consequences.<br>
In November 2017 a YouTube video creator working with two moderators of the 4chan website, began plugging specific anonymous posts (<a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/2017/12/qanon-4chan-the-storm-conspiracy-explained.html">dated October 2017</a>) pulled from amidst the many conspiracy theories posted on 4chan.</p>
<p>These conspiracy theories claimed they were authored by ‘Q’, who portended to be an anonymous high-ranking (US) military officer.  The theories therein espoused by Q – the world is run by an international child sacrifice and sexual abuse satanic cult controlled by senior democrats, only Donald Trump can save us – would result in QAnon transforming from conspiracy hobby to international cult with significant financial and political clout.</p>
<p>None of this is new information; it’s <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/tech-news/how-three-conspiracy-theorists-took-q-sparked-qanon-n900531">well documented</a> that the 3 individuals who picked out these posts by ‘Q’ and plugged them, have benefitted financially from the increased digital footfall they’ve experienced through their respective platforms.  It’s theorised that they probably authored these comments, or at least assumed the writing mantle at some point.  What’s not been covered, despite the fact it’s easily accessible to anyone with an internet connection, is the likely creative writing origin of QAnon; True Detective series 1 and the more obscure MotherHorseEyes narrative.</p>
<p>Satanic child murdering orchestrated and participated in by politicians is lifted right out of True Detective.  A narrative as cartoony and shocking as this is not hard to come up with.  It may be coincidental, harkening back to Medieval notions of Satanically inspired nobles with a penchant for doing the worst thing they could think of.  But = it’s a significant coincidence.   In fact it is exactly the same story.  And True Detective Season 1 came out in 2014 to critical acclaim, causing a spike in popularity for The King in Yellow, anything Carcosa, and helped reinvigorate Lovecratian fandom with the incredible sense of cosmic despair the expertly crafted series instils in the viewer.<br>
A lot of people have seen the series or at least heard about it, and the parallels are obvious.  What isn’t as mainstream is what occurred in July 2016, just over a year before the first post by ‘Q’ in October 2017: the ‘creepypasta’ <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/9M9H9E9/wiki/narrative">creative writing narrative</a> authored by _9MOTHER9HORSE9EYES9 (mother horse eyes).
This entertaining narrative took the form of a series of reddit posts release between April and July 2016, detailing several emergent narratives that came together.  It reads like the pitch for an excellent sci fi novel about the humanities destruction/enslavement at the hands of a superior consciousness, with a strong current of ‘flesh horror’ throughout.  The piece introduced a sinister, anonymous, otherworldly presence that acts as the Big Bad/protagonist throughout, and named it ‘Q’.  What Q is, is to a degree open to interpretation.  Nothing more has been published.  There’s been no book detail, no explanation, just a Reddit entry that gained large traction on it’s way to being lucratively monetised… and then stopped.  A mysterious entity called Q, named in a creative writing project on Reddit that managed to receive coverage in well-respected British Newspaper <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2016/may/05/9mother9horse9eyes9-the-mysterious-tale-terrifying-reddit">The Guardian</a>, seemingly disappeared from the creative writing scene.</p>
<p>Barely more than a year later a fictional character called Q was telling us that our children were being trafficked by Democrats who wanted to ritually sacrifice them in the name of Satan.  The 3 Amigos of thought crime, or a separate QAnon author, could simply have picked a letter in the alphabet they thought sounded cool (James Bonds long suffering Scientist is called Q).  But given the audacious hack rip off/copy &amp; paste True Detective plot line, the fact that mother horse eyes was well known amongst the Reddit community and the authors were active participants, the time line looks like one hell of a coincidence:</p>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/True_Detective_(season_1)">True Detective (2014)</a> &gt; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/9M9H9E9/wiki/narrative">9MOTHER9HORSE9EYES9 (2016)</a> &gt; <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/what-is-qanon-what-we-know-about-the-conspiracy-theory-11597694801">QAnon (2017)</a>.</p>
<p>Understanding this origin is essential to forming a rational picture of how the pieces came together.  Drawing attention to a Reddit piece about Flesh interfaces and cosmic horror -in order to frame the narrative origins of QAnon as a creative writing project monetised and subsequently weaponised - is a small but important battle in the war for our minds.  QAnon doesn’t end with TRUMP.  It has presented a monstrous narrative that railroads common sense into submission through emotive necessity, and has become the vehicle carrying numerous other conspiracies that may die or at least wither in isolation; vaccines are bad for you, 5G causes COVID, climate change is a lie, the Earth is flat.</p>
<p>As a species, from the earliest days of Palaeolithic campfires, we’ve thrived on stories; for the vast majority of our time of earth, oral tradition has been the primary means through which we preserve, modify and articulate our shared understanding of events and ideas.  This is reflected in the structure of our brain which is poorly optimised for written language analysis, compared with our capacity to communicate orally.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>(This is covered in detail in the excellent ‘<a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/546526/grasp-by-sanjay-sarma-with-luke-yoquinto/">Grasp</a>’ by Sanjay Sarma and Luke Yoquinto.)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Whilst our methodology for communicating has evolved rapidly, with technology far outpacing biological adaptation, understanding narrative is still essential to understanding what information really is.  We may have sophisticated written languages and IT tools, but our brains are broadly the same.  Data is nothing without some kind of validity or ‘truth’ assessment – a method with which to weigh it’s likely veracity common in intelligence services.</p>
<p>Depending on the individual, conspiracy thinking is either a failure in rationalisation (born from insecurity and driven by necessity), intellectual laziness, or a combination exacerbated by evolution;  our brains are pattern recognition machines continually seeking to conserve energy.  Born from necessity to survive, this often leads to entrenched views/polarisation, confirmation bias and ‘logic traps’, wherein a shared subjective reality with arbitrary and transient rules often Trumps objective reality.  Objective reality is an elusive concept when as individuals we have only one point of 1st hand reference.  But it’s there, and striving towards it should be the aim of any person seeking to evolve beyond the architecture of our being.  Or at least try to lengthen the distance between human communities and Baboon rock.</p>
<p>Monetised and/or weaponised conspiracy theories threaten our cognitive development.  We live in an era where selfmade millionaires and professionals who graduated high school sometimes believe the world is flat.  Understanding the narrative - the story - behind the demise of common sense is overlooked at our peril.</p>
<h3 id="recommended-listening">Recommended listening:</h3>
<p>An excellent of edition of the British Radio 4 podcast Analysis, presenting a candid and succinct assessment of the current era of conspiracy.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b006r4vz/topics/Conspiracy_theories">See here for the BBC site</a>
<a href="https://open.spotify.com/episode/50s0eEu3Fa0wodmHsDlhhY">Or here for the Spotify version</a></p>
<blockquote>
<h3 id="on-a-further-note">On a further note:</h3>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>I&rsquo;ve taken part in a critical thinking skills training course which involves a lesson and exercise in conspiracy thinking.  Syndicates are split for and against, and presented with conspiracy theories including Flat Earth and 5G.  They have to present an argument to the audience who vote on who seems the most convincing .<br>
The participants are generally high functioning ‘white collar’ professionals.  But the amateur conspiracy theorists broughthave always brought it home for the win.  Every time. Why?  Science is hard, Crusades are easy.  It’s more natural to form an emotional attachment to emotive sentiments than to cold hard facts.  Of course the audience knew it was baloney, but the lesson regarding how even well educated people can fall for nonsense hits home.<br>
There’s a palpable silence in the room when it does.</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Cyberpunk 2077 Review</title>
			<link>https://fightlikeacrow.com/posts/cyberpunk_2077_review/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 12:00:33 +0800</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://fightlikeacrow.com/posts/cyberpunk_2077_review/</guid>
			<description>To My Dear Comrade R, holed up in Sunny France…
A twisted Yuletide atmosphere is afoot in the UK this year. Christmas has been cancelled at the 11th hour by a sinister collective of political masochists, and a return to normality seems years away. The UK itself is a bus being stubbornly driven in the direction of a No Deal Cliff Edge, with an unqualified ego centrist at the wheel and a cohort of passengers who would literally rather die than speak up in front of their peers.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>To My Dear Comrade R, holed up in Sunny France…</p>
<p>A twisted Yuletide atmosphere is afoot in the UK this year. Christmas has been cancelled at the 11th hour by a sinister collective of political masochists, and a return to normality seems years away.  The UK itself is a bus being stubbornly driven in the direction of a No Deal Cliff Edge, with an unqualified ego centrist at the wheel and a cohort of passengers who would literally rather die than speak up in front of their peers.  Instead they gaze nervously out of the window, convincing the stranger next to them that either the cliff isn’t real or the valley floor is a wonderland of reduced Marks and Spencer Goodness, with prices slashed due to the lack of a Brussels Butter mountain tax.  Meanwhile the youth and the educated have fled to the back where they smoke poor quality weed and fantasise about carving a swastika into their Nans face.<br>
An Mp3 of Rule Britannia recorded by Bishops Heath 9-10 year school choir crackles in and out of silence on the semi broken bus radio.  A poor attempt to distract everyone from the lack of air conditioning and an onboard toilet that’s been blocked for years.  The Polish man who used to fix it is gone, and everyone else would rather just sit in their own filth waiting for employment fits around their Insta persona.</p>
<p>But amidst all this misery, a star was born.  One which had been spoken of in whispers for years past.  Promised but undelivered.   For a time it passed into mythology; a hero to save the salaried classes from their comfortable misery,  and allow them to wreak revenge on a virtual pastiche of the invisible hand they had so come to resent.  A game.  But not just any game.  THE game.  The best game of all time.  An immersive audio visual masterpiece to eclipse all that had come before: CYBERPUNK 2077.</p>
<p>But it didn’t go as planned…</p>
<p>And now you wonder, from your Parisian den of ill repute keeping one eye on your espresso and the other on the lookout for enthusiastic gendarmerie: “but how good is it really Daaave”.  Well, this is my 10 cents. It barely scratches the surface, but hopefully it will fill the yawning void of anticipation…</p>
<h3 id="the-short">The Short:</h3>
<p>It is one of the best games of all time, that does nothing new mechanically.  It will be one of the best versions of the mechanics it contains, but right now it’s one Beta development cycle away from being the experience people were expecting.  Despite this, even on my hardware it manages a truly unique feat: being simultaneously the most minorly buggy and smoothest running modern game I’ve ever played.  And it’s lots of fun.  And I love the story and the setting.  Just don’t expect the revolution here, or anywhere else for that matter.</p>
<h3 id="the-long-spoiler-free">The Long (Spoiler Free):</h3>
<p><strong>Actually playing it:</strong>  In the beginning there were enemies.  And they seemed to be made of cyber skin impervious to bullets.  Either that or your bullets were made of the same foam used to make Nerf darts.  But then you checked your inventory and realised you had a Katana with 3 x the DPS, and quickly discovered that sprinting at your enemies waving your sword like a lunatic screaming ‘I AM SPONGE DEATH’ whilst rapidly jabbing the ‘use health kit’ button, guaranteed success for at least the first 90 mins.  You quickly discovered that this was more fulfilling than creep crouching around like a pantomime Fred West at a Women’s Refuge.</p>
<p>Despite that, the combat is actually fun.  None of this ‘well it’s a good game rpg/mmorpg and the combat doesn’t make me want to climb a bell tower and start chimping’.  It is actually satisfying.  When you get some more powerful guns 2 hours in.  Before that the Katana rage tactic is surprisingly cathartic.
Stealth is nothing special, but works very well.  Plaudits to the level designers.  Presumably if you’ve suffered a mental breakdown and fancy playing this for 200 hours over the course of a week, an entirely stealthy play through is possible.  But, cutting cyborg gangbangers heads off with a sword when you catch them running a snuff clinic is infinitely more satisfying.  Although, looking at the 10 million units sold, the games clearly going to be played by some mentalists, so have it comrades.</p>
<p>The Netrunning side of it is largely missing.  Given the prevalence of the cyberspace realm in the original book, and spin offs such as Android Netrunner, it’s clear this could have been a vast game within the meta game.  But it’s not here.  It’s missing.  Lying dead on the cutting room floor so a 12 year old with a 30 year console can spend hours giggling over the vagina/penis options in 5FPS low res hell.  The hacking that does exist works at least, and the quick hacks in combat add a satisfying if simple extra dimension to puzzle solving your way through a mission.</p>
<p>As the game moves on, combat and looting get’s more and more fun with a very satisfying array of weapons, crafting and subsequent scrounging.  The world itself is enormous, and an absolute treat.  I’ve barely scratched the service.  Mission management is similar to the Witcher, with side quests and gigs generated through your progression and encounters.  There’s also random mad shit that happens, such as interrupting a drug deal or cleaning up the streets.  It’s satisfying to chance upon an organised crime deal going to down;  the phone rings, it’s the police dispatcher.  You’re pulled in by the lure of a hero complex, promise of dollar dollar bills and the potential for a shiny new shirt or sniper rifle.  Next moment you find yourself in a biblical scrap and when you eventually emerge victorious, you’ve completely forgotten what you were trying to do.  This plethora of simple yet satisfying activity in an enormous city is excellent.</p>
<p>Crafting’s in the game, and adds an effective means to ensure you can have a reasonable stab at equipping yourself the way you want to, otherwise you’re reliant on what the vendors are selling.  The Cyberware enhancements are fun and work well, dramatically improving your survivability and providing abilities such as double jump and fold out arm swords [there is a way to get legendary mantis arm blades for free – which is the only cheaty thing I recommend looking up].</p>
<p>The Story is enormously satisfying, but I am a captive audience.  Don’t expect True Detective Series 1 levels of craftsmanship, it’s mostly quite simple.  But, in the same vane as the Witcher, many of the plot pieces and side hustles are excellently scripted and suitably harrowing for this beautiful dystopia.
One particular thing I’ve noticed is that loading times are very quick, which makes the below easier to grapple with…</p>
<p><strong>The bugs.</strong>  I can hear the spiders scratching at the insides of your brain, whispering doubts and promises of disappointment; perhaps you’ll hit play and find your freezer cooled GPU reduced to slag.  The bugs are minor and prolific, mostly graphical, and often solved by reloading.  For a minority of players they are a game killer; one particular favourite is that your save games break if they get too big through crafting prolifically (??).  You simply have to roll the dice with what you’ve got.  But you’ll probably be ok.  I’ll extrapolate conservatively/rant aggressively about why these bugs are here at all later in the article [on Sunday the studio admitted the assertion that many have made; they tried to make a next gen game for a last gen console.  Because, money * shareholders / financial forecasts].</p>
<p><strong>The Reviews:</strong> So many poor reviews.  It’s understandable with respect to the bugs, the reviewer version of the game was in even poorer shape than the launch.  Even if we know most of these will eventually be fixed.  But many criticised the game itself for not being ‘new’ or ‘innovative’. WTF did reviewers expect?  It’s like being promised the second coming and meeting a friendly Israeli guy who builds you a beautiful table and let’s you use his home gym.  You’ve got a sweet deal but you can’t help resenting the fact that your ludicrous-to-the point-of-being-abstractly-fictional-expectations were not fulfilled.  There will be no truly innovative AAA games until the industry sees innovative technology.  The same issues that affect video games now, affected them in the 90’s; the AIs difficult to program and scale, visuals are capped by the mean state of technology within the demographic you’re appealing to, and all current technology is just a better, faster more powerful version of what came before.  There are promising signs of change with respect to super computers application in programming and scaling AI in addition to pre-rendering 4 &amp; 8k visuals for various chipsets.  But until working the cost in terms of money and time into a developmental cycle becomes standard, this will remain fringe.  If Cyberpunks reviews highlighted anything, it’s how arbitrary a number score can be when the criteria are not accurately unpacked.  Hence my attempt at the end of this to quantify my judgement of the work.
But why all the bugs?</p>
<p><strong>They got greedy.</strong>  The 8-year enterprise is atypical of the current state of gaming economics.  Being driven entirely by short termist shareholder interest, CDPR had no practical choice but to appeal to the widest section of playable society they theoretically could.  They were forced by the status quo of AAA economics to make their game playable on 2 generations of console, the second not being released until 2 months before the eventual game release.  This was despite the fact that this was first and foremost a PC release, taking advantage of a revolution of GPU power in relative terms.  This ridiculous technological balancing act meant they sacrificed features for player count, and were at best naive, if not outright liars regarding the release date to attract shareholder interest and pre-release investment.  Their rhetoric undid them in the end, and the game became too big to delay any further, with Christmas 2020 set to be too lucrative a period for the investors to miss out on.</p>
<p>The Fall of Cyberpunk, at least in the immediate future, is a fitting allegory for short term market economics strangling and frustrating the capacity of the human race to realise it’s technological potential.  Whilst it is only a video game, it’s popularity transcends boundaries of frivolity to make a poignant point; the supposedly exponential curve of technology is being curb stomped by short term economics.  What this means for Video games is more of the same: Indie games will push the boundaries of mechanics, relying predominantly on PC power and KBM input to realise untapped potential, whereas the Audio Visual AAA overheads with their requisite exorbitant development costs will remain trapped in dealing with the lowest common denominator; console customers with last years GPU masquerading as a computation system.</p>
<p>budget gaming is set to continue to be apolitical, unartistic and certainly not innovative.  We can only hope for the Half Life exceptions that somehow break through.
Until Supercomputers are commonly used to develop (and scale) innovative systems such as gaming AI and visual performance, the revolution is one giant fuck off wall of economic NOPE away.  Expect more of the same, but gradually prettier.  Forever.</p>
<p>Having a layer of non-developing Suit management living in Narnia and conjuring PowerPoint charts made of dreams and pixel art for hungry CDPR investors certainly didn’t help.  A noticeable quirk of the industry, and perhaps part of the reason behind the success of indie studios (and the existence of the Early Access model), is that in the most critically successful studios the layer of Suit management between Investor and Developer is largely absent, or at least silent.  Given that large studios are the only organisations with the resources to produce AAA titles, the future of depressingly ordinary.</p>
<p>Putting away the whisky and the soapbox, does any of this matter for playing Cyberpunk?  No.  It’s a very fun game, one of the best ever made provided your hardware doesn’t produce game breaking bugs and you dig the aesthetic.  I’m having lots of fun – I am addicted.  And I’m still amazed at how smooth the experience is on my modest laptop.  But it has made me realise how very far away the future is.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>The Cult of anxiety; what direction is forward, Discussion</title>
			<link>https://fightlikeacrow.com/posts/the-cult-of-anxiety-what-direction-is-forward-a-discussion/</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 11:36:33 +0800</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://fightlikeacrow.com/posts/the-cult-of-anxiety-what-direction-is-forward-a-discussion/</guid>
			<description>TRN Initial Assertion: #Metoo, BLM, and other movements striving for justice within a given social and/or geographic space have been partly consumed by an all-encompassing, homogenous movement (despite its heterogeneous roots) that has become known as Woke culture. Far from creating a new renaissance for equality and meritocracy, this movement is damaging the evolution of human rights by dismissing moderates, liberals and rationalists, It has been high-jacked or subsumed by a generational groundswell of anxiety addled, predominantly Caucasian, ardent reactionaries.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="trn-initial-assertion">TRN Initial Assertion:</h2>
<p>#Metoo, BLM, and other movements striving for justice within a given social and/or geographic space have been partly consumed by an all-encompassing, homogenous movement (despite its heterogeneous roots) that has become known as Woke culture. Far from creating a new renaissance for equality and meritocracy, this movement is damaging the evolution of human rights by dismissing moderates, liberals and rationalists,  It has been high-jacked or subsumed by a generational groundswell of anxiety addled, predominantly Caucasian, ardent reactionaries.</p>
<p>This group is abusing political and social imperatives, such as developing expectations with regards to sexual and gender identity, to furiously assault any mechanism through which their bubble of emotional sanctity may be breached.  This cult of anxiety embodies all the characteristics of an overtly emotive and irrational religion that remains stubbornly dissonant from facts.  It may harm or destroy the vital causes and vulnerable people it seeks to champion.</p>
<p>It is anti-liberal in its assault of pretensions to rationality, and anti-conservation in its attempts to deny or destroy history by preventing objective based discourse that may incite emotive offense within a protected social margin.
Ironically in attempting to support the notion of natural equality amongst humans (a central tenant of the French revolution), it has inadvertently become a form of fascism synonymous with the repression of rational thought, repression of history and proposed dominance of cultural norms that suit a hyper-reactive fringe group.</p>
<p>Any movement regardless of intention that moves humanity away from the objective to the subjective with respect to our shared collective reality is toxic.  It’s popularity will causate with the ability for cruel fringe elements to enjoy increased influence within the political stratum. Current generations must be forced to become comfortable with being uncomfortable in order to ensure the shared delusion of society is as close to the facts as possible; it’s through intellectual and physical rigour that we learn to alleviate our anxiety without eroding the delicate framework that exists to propel society towards a fairer and more meritocratic existence. Our academic institutions must be immune from emotive dissent whilst providing a rational forum within which it can be expressed.</p>
<p>Wokeness has noble ambitions, but like most emotive political movements, it has regressed into yet another ugly, repressive source of polarisation.</p>
<p>Pragmatic compassion is needed now more than ever or we risk de-volving as culture.</p>
<h3 id="m">M:</h3>
<p>Something that is missing is the fact that a driver for the Woke culture is the fact that our generation and GenZ even more lack patience so people want to see change ASAP and become more aggressive.</p>
<p>The other thing is the mention of objective v. subjective. I get that you are trying to establish that rational debate cannot be marred with appeals to emotions w/o facts but it&rsquo;s undeniable that emotions need to be involved to inspire masses and to promote a cultural change.</p>
<p>The fact that &ldquo;social justice movements&rdquo; are tackling multidisciplinary interconnected problems means that it&rsquo;s too difficult to have purely fact-based discussions and that&rsquo;s why they devolve to appeals to consciousness and ignore rationality. The other consequence is that correlation between a lot of factors gives plenty of opportunities for status quo proponents to handpick &ldquo;facts&rdquo; that are contrary to where we should be as a society.  Or (as seen from several conservatives nowadays) gish-gallop to reduce the influence from the other debating side, by reinforcing dated views while putting the onus on them to sift through the crap.</p>
<h3 id="trn">TRN:</h3>
<p>I agree.  I believe the wider generational issue is one of a lack of applied behavioural intelligence; I’ll quantify that as a lack of basic behavioural competence such as patience, anxiety management and/or impulse control.  This is exacerbated by the seemingly exponential increase in the speed with which information travels (and the unlimited breadth of audience), correlated with autonomous segmentation due to market oriented algorithms. As a result I think any emotive issue becomes characterised by behaviour adults would not tolerate in children.</p>
<p>The architecture for debate and cognitive development in general has not kept up with societal expectations or the increased glut in non-provable information.  The Medieval equivalent believe the mad raving alchemist because they guessed gravity right. Now everyone sleeps with a pig ear under the pillow so faeries don’t eat their nose.  Better safe than sorry.</p>
<p>Exacerbating all of this is a complete failure to instil Utopian thinking within 1st world democracies; without a concept of what we want Society to be and what we don&rsquo;t want it to be, there&rsquo;s no shared reality from which to infer recognisable meaning, or shared context.  The result is a fractured mess of echo chambers, some well-intentioned others not, being wittingly preyed upon by market algorithms looking for short term shareholder gains. Belief in the FreeMarket as an self-writing ecosystem is itself a religion.  It challenges all hints of regulation control as being antithetical or even heretical for what is &lsquo;good&rsquo; for our future as a race.</p>
<p>It’s impossible to imagine a world without some model of capitalism short of a Science Fiction techno revolution; we are all monkeys after all.  But FreeMarket capitalism has transcended from economic system to religion, or even cult.  FreeMarket is a pernicious system within which democratically elected control or influence of the system is viciously assaulted in the minds of the electorate, with economic devastation being the hell on earth waiting for heretics who question it’s modus operandi. It is itself a macro level algorithm propagated by a tiny minority of wealth accumulators, for whom long term devastation is a irrelevant where their short term financial success.</p>
<p>It is enabled through it’s dark marriage with religion; most importantly conservative septs of Christianity within the USA (which is the primary arbiter of State sanctioned FreeMarket/anti-regulation doctrine).  Why worry that the Future of humanity as at stake, when an omnipresent trans-dimensional space wizard can fix everything with a click of it’s/His fingers?</p>
<p>Also, [erhaps the historical roots of the FreeMarket religion are at least partly reflected in the birth of ecology, which became a Gaian movement proposing that the Earth was a perfect self-righting organism.  <strong>Since disproven by reality</strong>.  <em>I would also refer to our Saurian ancestors for comment if they hadn’t been annihilated by an explosive cause of wrong place wrong time.</em></p>
<p>Whilst notions of utopia conjure horrifying visions of atrocities, in reality when politics doesn&rsquo;t provide a vision of the future that space is filled by reactionary fear mongers and asinine short term corporate interest (that ironically hurts the bottom line in the long run). In this context fascism wins, which means we all lose.</p>
<p>A world run by short term commercial interest will kill us off long before we can evolve in a sustainable and compassionate manner.  The FreeMarket religion is a paradigm that needs to be shattered for survival, let alone happiness.  A cult of anxiety is not going to help – anxious people make anxious choices.</p>
<p>Also I don&rsquo;t think younger generations aren’t any less intelligent objectively, rather all generations appear less intelligent in practise due to the outdated architecture for regulating communication on any large scale. I think younger generations have it even harder because they lack any firsthand context for being unconnected and forced to debate amongst peers. Private education can compensate for this but state education is typically under the intellectual yolk of Skinners asinine views that amount to bureaucratic narcissism. The toxic heart of this is buoyed by a FreeMarket hegemony pandering to the cult of anxiety that will figuratively devour adult children. No one feels good being made to feel uncomfortable, but it’s an absolute requirement for empathic and effective people.  Without a strong academic architecture to support the critical development of young people, we are in a bad place</p>
<h3 id="m-1">M:</h3>
<p>Going back to the bread of that sandwich. It&rsquo;s a mix of expectations, effort and nature which as you rightly point out is playing against the very folk that want to drive change.</p>
<p><em>Effort:</em> People being lazy thinkers is not new. Hell, half of the discussion points from the fathers of philosophy are just about the nature of questioning and forming opinion with calculated distance to be aware of discoveries from an opposing point of view. That was already difficult when there was no printing press and most information travelled slowly. We&rsquo;ve discussed this aplenty but it&rsquo;s part of the problem and I feel that there is a resurgence of methods and frameworks to analyse information after the whole fake news debacle but that matters only to people willing to put the effort. In a world of blogs, blue checkmarks and &ldquo;content&rdquo;, it is easy to be an expert and have followers even if you talk pure crap. Fox News being a great example.</p>
<p><em>Expectations:</em> We are exposed to all kinds of information all the time in an era where we&rsquo;ve done more in 150 years to radically change society over and over than most of recorded history combined. We are all expected to have strong opinions fast, to be able to discuss matters across all subjects and to keep up with the order of the day. That is combined with effort above&hellip; What is the minimum effort necessary to keep up with those expectations?</p>
<p><em>Nature:</em> The echo chamber. Feeling good. Avoiding confrontation and getting endorphins from group-wide acknowledgement. It&rsquo;s very difficult to escape any of these things for any of us. We didn&rsquo;t grow up on TikTok politics but if I had I wonder how much effort I would invest in getting out of that cycle. Hell&hellip; Our elders love the f**ing WhatsApp chains because it makes them feel good, like they hold some truth.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s all combined and exactly as you&rsquo;re saying. The current gen is expected to hold more information, tackle more areas, sift through more sources, still overcome our nature to recognise patters and trends even when they&rsquo;re not there and fight back in the same establishment that was designed for a different era.</p>
<p>Some of the questions on your original essay still stand though. Being subjective, keeping up with anxiety, wanting to solve issues before the next problem highlighted hours in the future comes along, seem to be consequences rather than root causes. Is there something more fundamental missing to prevent Woke culture from swallowing and distorting the movements created, to address real and fundamental issues in our society as it stands?</p>
<h3 id="trn-1">TRN:</h3>
<p>The Fascist tendencies of woke culture, however ironic and self -destructive, are the result of the architecture (or lack of) that we have for regulating the flow, consideration and articulation of information, which is partly driven by a short termist exponential growth market algorithm which I truly believe has become an evangelical religion, and largely impervious to questioning/rationalisation.</p>
<p>The long-term goals of regulating and orienting the market towards ascribing value based on the future we want humanity to experience is a lofty goal.  A shared sense of Utopia is mostly limited to cultural platitudes riven with fault lines (such as secular governance vs non governance).  However, there are generic shared realities that are innate within all of us; for example our physical, mental and emotional reliance on the environment.  Despite this, regulating a system controlled by the US hegemony in the age of the bi partisan Republican is daunting, if not unachievable.</p>
<p>In terms of what fundamental can be addressed that is practically achievable, basic critical thinking and behavioural skills are more important than ever, to equip humans for the unrelenting barrage of anxious cruelty they are assailed with the moment they connect with any (social)media.  To accomplish this, the education system should be gutted and completed re-designed.  It should orientate foundationally around the behavioural skillset that society wants to see in a productive, mentally healthy citizen, that is intellectually equipped to exercise sufficient patience and purpose in moving the societal agenda for equality further towards a sane/pragmatic conception of meritocracy.  <em>Whilst safeguarding the basic requirement to have a discourse around a topic that inspires differing opinions.</em></p>
<p>The public education of the population majority is perhaps the silver bullet for necessitating change in the age of technology and time is limited; the techno aristocracy (i.e. Googles owners) will literally die out and be replaced by faceless shareholder interest within a generation or two.  The opportunity to seize conscious control of the zeitgeist will perhaps be lost.</p>
<p>With education using a therapy approach to instilling a love for learning underpinned by the development of a cognitive and behavioural skillset fit for a secular, rational society, we will garden a kinder world.</p>
<p>Whilst this too appears to be ludicrously optimistic, that hard part; the infrastructure, the laws forcing young people to be there etc, is taken care of.  What’s holding us back?  I think a lack of requirement analysis which is the result of an invisible future, obscured by a miasma of Reaganite nothing politics is to blame.  Some Western countries are terrible at planning beyond year long ministerial appointments that serve a party leader and not the public sector (when’s the last time any minister of education was a former teacher?)/</p>
<p>I think you hit the nail by referring to &ldquo;social justice movements […] tackling multidisciplinary interconnected problems”.  In this environment the most provocative meme takes social precedence.  It’s perhaps too late for us, but if we act now we can save the next generation, and maybe even undo some of the harm.</p>
<p>A requirement analysis of our respective countries national curriculums oriented around behavioural intelligence/critical thinking skills development, in order to produce more considerate citizens, is the silver artillery shell we are looking for.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
