<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FIGHT LIKE A CROW</title>
    <link>https://fightlikeacrow.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on FIGHT LIKE A CROW</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 11:36:33 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fightlikeacrow.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Creative Writing Origin of QAnon</title>
      <link>https://fightlikeacrow.com/posts/the-creative-writing-origin-of-qanon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 11:36:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fightlikeacrow.com/posts/the-creative-writing-origin-of-qanon/</guid>
      <description>Media outlets have failed to report the likely creative writing origins of QAnon. This oversight is extremely important with respect to undermining the narrative of shameless QAnon aficionados who have turned a creative writing exercise into something between a doomsday cult and a pyramid scheme, with real life consequences.
In November 2017 a YouTube video creator working with two moderators of the 4chan website, began plugging specific anonymous posts (dated October 2017) pulled from amidst the many conspiracy theories posted on 4chan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cyberpunk 2077 Review</title>
      <link>https://fightlikeacrow.com/posts/cyberpunk_2077_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 12:00:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fightlikeacrow.com/posts/cyberpunk_2077_review/</guid>
      <description>To My Dear Comrade R, holed up in Sunny France…
A twisted Yuletide atmosphere is afoot in the UK this year. Christmas has been cancelled at the 11th hour by a sinister collective of political masochists, and a return to normality seems years away. The UK itself is a bus being stubbornly driven in the direction of a No Deal Cliff Edge, with an unqualified ego centrist at the wheel and a cohort of passengers who would literally rather die than speak up in front of their peers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cult of anxiety; what direction is forward, Discussion</title>
      <link>https://fightlikeacrow.com/posts/the-cult-of-anxiety-what-direction-is-forward-a-discussion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 11:36:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fightlikeacrow.com/posts/the-cult-of-anxiety-what-direction-is-forward-a-discussion/</guid>
      <description>##TRN Initial Assertion:##
#Metoo, BLM, and other movements striving for justice within a given social and/or geographic space have been partly consumed by an all-encompassing, homogenous movement (despite its heterogeneous roots) that has become known as Woke culture. Far from creating a new renaissance for equality and meritocracy, this movement is damaging the evolution of human rights by dismissing moderates, liberals and rationalists, It has been high-jacked or subsumed by a generational groundswell of anxiety addled, predominantly Caucasian, ardent reactionaries.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
